Guide to the Sherrie Maricle Collection, 1997-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Sherrie Maricle collection 1997-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Maricle, Sherrie
0.6 Linear Feet 100 Items
Sherrie Maricle (b. 1963) is a drummer, bandleader, composer, and educator. She directs the jazz groups Five Play, The Diva Jazz Trio, and The Diva Jazz Orchestra.
The Sherrie Maricle Collection contains press kits and compact discs of commercial studio recordings by Five Play, The Diva Jazz Trio, and The Diva Jazz Orchestra.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Sherrie Maricle Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in August 2009.
Biographical Note
Jazz drummer, bandleader, composer, and educator Sherrie Maricle (born Buffalo, N.Y., 2 Sept, 1963) studied clarinet, cello, and drums as a child. She began her professional musical career while an undergraduate at Binghamton University (BA 1986) and continued her career while pursuing additional studies at New York University (MA 1988, PhD 2000). Maricle currently performs with and leads the all female bands The Diva Jazz Orchestra, Five Play (jazz quintet), and The Diva Jazz Trio. She also performs with The New York Pops while serving as the orchestra's Director of Education. Maricle's awards include a Kennedy Center Alliance Award for Outstanding Achievements in the Arts, and a Lifetime Achievement Award at the 2009 Mary Lou Williams Women in Jazz Festival.
Collection Overview
The Sherrie Maricle Collection contains press kits for The Diva Jazz Orchestra (a 15 member all-female jazz big band) and Five Play (an all-female jazz quintet), both directed by Sherrie Maricle. The kits include publicity photographs, album and concert reviews, and biographical information on the group members. The collection also contains audio compact discs of commercially available recordings by The Diva Jazz Orchestra, The Diva Jazz Trio, and Five Play.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Compact discs
Diva (Musical group)
Five Play (Musical group)
Jazz
Jazz -- 1991-2000
Jazz -- 2001-2010
Maricle, Sherrie
New York (N.Y.)
Photographs
Women drummers (Musicians)
Women jazz musicians -- United States
Contents of Collection
- Press Kits, (2 folders)
  - Diva Jazz Orchestra Press Kit (Box 1)
  - Five Play Press Kit
- Commercial Audio CDs, 1997-2009, (9 Audio CDs)
  - The Diva Jazz Orchestra: I Believe in You (1999) (Box 1)
  - The Diva Jazz Orchestra: Leave it to Diva (1997)
  - The Diva Jazz Orchestra: Live From Jazz at Lincoln Center's Dizzy's Coca Cola Club (2008)
  - The Diva Jazz Orchestra: Live in Concert (2002)
  - The Diva Jazz Orchestra: A Tommy Newsom Tribute (Lightyear, 54698-2: 2005)
  - The Diva Jazz Trio: Never Never Land (Arbors Records, ARCD 19393: 2009)
  - Five Play: On the Brink (Arbors Records, ARCD 19218: 1999)
  - Five Play: Plus (Arbors Records, ARCD 19307: 2004)
  - Five Play: What the World Needs Now (Arbors Records, ARCD 19381: 2008)